linuxacademy.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy – Linux Academy

Effective Date: _May 25th, 2018_  
Last Updated: _May 22nd, 2018_

#### Introduction

This Privacy Policy applies to all data collection by Linux Academy, Inc. (“Linux Academy” or “we”) and shall apply to your use of this website, your use of any affiliated third party websites that may contain a link to this Privacy Policy, or to any pages, facilities, services, or capabilities accessible on or by any top-level Linux Academy domain owned by us (each, a “Site” and collectively the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Linux Academy collects information from you (“User” or “you”) on the Sites.

Our Privacy Policy explains: (1) what information we collect and why we collect it; (2) how we use that information; (3) the choices we offer, including how to access and update information. Specifically, our Privacy Policy covers the following topics:

  1. When This Privacy Policy Applies
  2. Terms of Service
  3. Information We Collect
  4. How We Use Information We Collect
  5. Our Legal Basis for Collecting Personal Data
  6. Information We Share
  7. Your Failure to Provide Personal Data
  8. Our Retention of Your Personal Data
  9. Your Choices and Accessing, Updating or Deleting Your Personal Data
  10. Our Opt-in/Out-out Policy
  11. Third Party Links
  12. International Transfer
  13. How We Protect Personal Data
  14. Children
  15. “Do Not Track” Signals
  16. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  17. How to Contact Us

Please familiarize yourself with our privacy practices and let us know if you have any questions. By using the Sites, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites.

#### When this Privacy Policy Applies

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by Linux Academy, and services offered on other sites, but excludes services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy Policy.

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals, including products or sites that may be displayed to you, or other sites linked from our services. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organizations who advertise our services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to serve and offer relevant ads.

#### Terms of Service

By accessing or using the Sites in any manner, you also agree to be bound by Linux Academy’s Terms of Service (the “Agreement”). Please read the Agreement carefully. If you do not accept all of the terms and conditions contained in or incorporated by reference into the Agreement, please do not use the Sites.

#### Information We Collect

We collect information, including personal data, to provide better services to all our Users. We use the term “Personal Data” to refer to any information that identifies or can be used to identify you. Common examples of personal data include: full name, home address, email address, date of birth, digital identity, such as a login name or handle, information about your device, and certain metadata.

“Sensitive Personal Data” refers to a smaller subset of personal data which is considered more sensitive to the individual, such as race and ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, genetic or biometric information, physical or mental health information, medical insurance data, or sexual orientation. Linux Academy does **not** collect or use Sensitive Personal Data and asks that you do **not** provide Sensitive Personal Data to us.

We collect Personal Data in the following ways:

  1.  **Information You Give to Us**

You may choose to provide us with personal data about yourself by completing forms on our website, such as when you register to use our services. You may also provide us with Personal Data about yourself when your report a problem or have a question about our services.

Please note that if you do not provide us with Personal Data, your ability to use certain aspects of our products and services may be limited.

  2.  **Information We Obtain from Your Use of Our Services**

We collect certain information automatically, such as your operating system version, browser type, and internet service provider. When you use our Site, we automatically collect and store this information in service logs. This includes: details of how you used our Site; Internet protocol address; and cookies that uniquely identify your browser. We may also collect and process information about your location. The information we collect automatically is statistical data and may or may not include Personal Data, but we may maintain it or associate it with Personal Data we collect in other ways or receive from third parties.

  3.  **Cookies and Similar Technologies**

We and our partners use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit one of our services, and this may include using cookies or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. We also use these technologies to collect and store information when you interact with services from our partners, such as advertising services. Our third party advertising and analytics partners include, but are not limited to, Google, Hubspot, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Google Plus, VWO, Google Analytics, Olark, Intercom, Mailchimp, Sendgrid, SurveyMonkey, and Typeform.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

 **Cookies**. A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our services. For more information about our use of cookies, including details on how to opt-out of certain cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.

 **Web Beacons**. Pages of our services or our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

#### How We Use Information We Collect

We use your personal data in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or authorized by you, including for the following purposes:

  1. To inform you about services available from Linux Academy;
  2. To administer content, promotion, survey or other Site features;
  3. To communicate about, and administer your participation in, special programs, surveys, contests, and other offers or promotions, and to deliver pertinent emails;
  4. To improve our customer service and user experience;
  5. To respond to and support customers regarding their use of the Site, including billing;
  6. To comply with all applicable legal requirements.

We use the information we collect from our Site to provide, maintain, and improve them, to develop new services, and to protect our Company and our customers.

We use information collected from cookies and other technologies, to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services. For example, by saving your language preferences, we’ll be able to have our services appear in the language you prefer. We may use your personal information to see which web pages you visit at our Site, which web site you visited before coming to our Site, and where you go after you leave our Site. We can then develop statistics that help us understand how our visitors use our Site and how to improve it. We may also use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

We will ask for your consent before using information for a purpose other than those set out in this Privacy Policy.

#### Our Legal Basis for Collecting Personal Data

Whenever we collect Personal Data from you, we may do so on the following legal basis:

  1. Your consent to such collection and use;
  2. Out of necessity for the performance of an agreement between us and you, such as your agreement to use our services and products;
  3. Our legitimate business interest, including but not limited to the following circumstances where collecting or using Personal Data is necessary for:
    * Intra-company transfers for client data for administrative purposes;
    * Product development and enhancement, where the processing enables Linux Academy to enhance, modify, personalize, or otherwise improve our services and communications for the benefit of our customers, and to better understand how people interact with our Sites;
    * Communications and marketing, including processing data for direct marketing purposes, and subject to your opt-in for these purposes, and to determine the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and advertising;
    * Fraud detection and prevention;
    * Enhancement of our cybersecurity, including improving the security of our network and information systems; and
    * General business operations and diligence;
    * Records retention

Provided that, in each circumstance, we will weigh the necessity of our processing for the purpose against your privacy and confidentiality interests, including taking into account your reasonable expectations, the impact of processing, and any safeguards which are or could be put in place. In all circumstances, we will limit such processing for our legitimate business interest to what is necessary for its purposes.

#### Information We Share

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of the Company unless one of the following circumstances applies:

  *  **With your consent**. We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Linux Academy when we have your consent to do so.
  *  **For external processing**. We provide personal information to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or partners to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. These third parties include: Hubspot, GA, Intercom, Olark, Mailchip, SurveyMonkey, Google, Type Form, VWO, Sendgrid, and Zendesk. We do not share personal information with third parties for their own marketing purposes.
  *  **For Legal Reasons**. We will share Personal Data with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Linux Academy if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:
    * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
    * enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.
    * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
    * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Linux Academy, our Users or the public as required or permitted by law.
  *  **Business Transfers**. As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, sell, or share assets in connection with, for example, a merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets, or bankruptcy. In such transactions, Personal Data about our users is often a transferred business asset. In the event that Linux Academy itself or substantially all of our assets are acquired, Personal Data about our users may be one of the transferred assets.
  *  **Aggregate Site Use Information**. We may share aggregate and anonymized/pseudonymized Personal Data to advertisers and other third parties in order to promote or describe use of the Sites.

#### Your Failure to Provide Personal Data

Your provision of Personal Data is required in order to use certain parts of our services and our products. If you fail to provide such Personal Data, you may not be able to access and use our services and/or our products, or parts of our services and/or our products.

#### Our Retention of Your Personal Data

We may retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection. For example, we keep your Personal Data for no longer than reasonably necessary for your use of our products and services and for a reasonable period of time afterward. We also may retain your Personal Data during the period of time needed for us to pursue our legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

#### Your Choices and Accessing, Updating or Deleting Your Personal Data

Whenever you use our services, we aim to provide you with choices about how we use your personal data. We also aim to provide you with access to your Personal Data. If that information is wrong, we strive to give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. Subject to applicable law, you may obtain a copy of personal information we maintain about you or you may update or correct inaccuracies in that information through your Linux Academy account at www.linuxacademy.com, or by contacting us. To help protect your privacy and maintain security, we will take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the information. In addition, if you believe that personal information we maintain about you is inaccurate, subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request that we correct or amend the information by contacting us as indicated in the How to Contact Us section below.

  *  **European Users’ Rights With Respect to Personal Data**

Some data protection laws, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), provide you with certain rights in connection with Personal Data you have shared with us. If you are resident in the European Economic Area, you may have the following rights:

    1.  **The right to be informed**. You are entitled to be informed of the use of your Personal Data. This Privacy Policy provides such information to you.
    2.  **The right of access**. You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data which we hold about you.
    3.  **The right of correction** : You have the right to request correction or changes of your Personal Data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date.
    4.  **The right to be forgotten** : You have the right to request us, at any time, to delete your Personal Data from our servers and to erase your Personal Data when it is no longer necessary for us to retain such data. Note, however, that deletion of your Personal Data will likely impact your ability to use our services.
    5.  **The right to object (opt-out)** : You have the right to opt-out of certain uses of your Personal Data, such as direct marketing, at any time.
    6.  **The right to data portability** : You have the right to a “portable” copy of your Personal Data that you have submitted to us. Generally, this means your right to request that we move, copy or transmit your Personal Data stored on our servers / IT environment to another service provider’s servers / IT environment.
    7.  **The right to refuse to be subjected to automated decision making, including profiling** : You have the right not to be subject to a decision and insist on human intervention if the decision is based on automated processing and produces a legal effect or a similarly significant effect on you.
    8.  **The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.**
  *  **Changing or Deleting Your Information**

You may update or correct information about yourself by emailing us at [support@linuxacademy.com](mailtto:support@linuxacademy.com). If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law, to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements or for other legitimate business purposes.

We may contact you to request that you update your Personal Data on a regular basis to ensure its integrity for the purposes of ongoing data management.

#### Our Opt-in/Opt-out Policy

By providing an email address on the Linux Academy Sites, you agree that we may contact you in the event of a change in this Privacy Policy, to provide you with any service related notices, or to provide you with information about our events, invitations, or related educational information.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “opt-in” is generally defined as any affirmative action by a user to submit or receive information, as the case may be.

We currently provide the following opt-out opportunities:

  1. At any time, you can follow a link provided in offers, newsletters or other email messages (except for e-commerce confirmation or service notice emails) received from us to unsubscribe.
  2. At any time, you can contact us through [support@linuxacademy.com](mailto:support@linuxacademy.com) or the address or telephone number provided below to unsubscribe from the service and opt-out of our right per your consent under the terms of this Privacy Policy to share your Personal Data.

Notwithstanding anything else in this Privacy Policy, please note that we always reserve the right to contact you in the event of a change in this Privacy Policy, or to provide you with any service related notices.

#### Third Party Links

The Sites may contain links to web-pages operated by parties other than Linux Academy. We do not control such websites and are not responsible for their contents or the privacy policies or other practices of such websites. Our inclusion of links to such websites does not imply any endorsement of the material on such websites or any association with their operators. Further, it is up to the User to take precautions to ensure that whatever links the User selects or software the User downloads (whether from this Site or other websites) is free of such items as viruses, worms, trojan horses, defects and other items of a destructive nature. These websites and services may have their own privacy policies, which the User will be subject to upon linking to the third party’s website. Linux Academy strongly recommends that each User review the third party’s terms and policies.

#### International Transfer

We are committed to complying with applicable laws, regulations and mandatory government standards regarding the protection of Personal Data.

Since we are a global organization, Personal Data and any additional information submitted may be used globally in connection with employment, business processes within Linux Academy, or communicating with our clients. Therefore, Personal Data may be transferred to other Linux Academy entities worldwide, where it will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and laws that are applicable in each country.

If we transfer your Personal Data out of your jurisdiction, we will implement suitable safeguards to ensure that your Personal Data is protected. We are soon to be certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield and it is our policy to, where required by applicable laws, execute a Data Privacy & Data Security Addendum with all third parties with whom we may share Personal Data.

#### How We Protect Personal Data

Linux Academy maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the User’s Personal Data and information against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. We implement appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk, taking into account technological reality, cost, the scope, context and purposes of processing weighted against the severity and likelihood that the processing could threaten individual rights and freedoms. For example, we use commercially reasonable security measures such as encryption, firewalls, and transport layer security (TLS) or hypertext transfer protocol secure (HTTPS) to protect Personal Data.

If Linux Academy collects account information for payment or credit, Linux Academy will use the information only to complete the task for which the account information was offered.

#### Children

The Site is not intended for use by children. We do not intentionally gather Personal Data about visitors who are under the age of 13. If a child has provided us with Personal Data, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us to have the information deleted from our records. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please contact us at hunter@linuxacademy.com. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected the personal information of a child under 13, or equivalent minimum age depending on jurisdiction, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

#### “Do Not Track” Signals

Linux Academy does not track its customers over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, your browser may include controls to block and delete cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, to allow you to opt out of data collection through those technologies.

California residents are entitled to contact us to request information about whether we have disclosed personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. We do not disclose personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing us at the address listed in the “How to Contact Us” section.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services or products, email notification or privacy policy changes). We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

 **Contact**

If you have any questions or need to contact us about this policy, please contact:

Linux Academy   
Attn: Hunter Ferrell   
125 Bear Creek Parkway   
Keller, TX 76248
